Every engineering team has a memory problem.
The fix for last quarter's incident lives in a closed ticket, a Slack thread, or someone's head.
And half of that tribal knowledge is stale — the workaround everyone remembers was replaced two releases ago.
PatchPilot is incident memory that never goes stale.
It's built end-to-end on Cognee's memory lifecycle — remember, recall, improve, forget —
and you're about to watch every one of those four verbs work, live.
Sign-up and sign-in are real — Clerk auth with email or OAuth.
I'll sign in with GitHub — and that choice is about to matter,
because PatchPilot treats your repo as a memory source, not just a login.
This is remember. My GitHub username came from the sign-in — I pick a repo, hit Sync Now,
and its real issues become incident memory — each one through Cognee's add and cognify, into a knowledge graph.
And sync is incremental: next click only pulls issues opened since this one. Continuous memory, not a one-time import.
Now the on-call moment: users aren't getting password-reset emails.
I search — and PatchPilot recalls the incident with a recommendation, a real confidence score,
and the exact evidence chunks it's grounded in — graph search fused with chunk-level evidence.
Note the answer: run the flush_mail_queue script. That was the right fix… in version 1.8.
Then release one-point-nine ships, migrating email to the SendGrid API. I upload the release note —
and watch the old workaround. PatchPilot flagged it red — drifting —
with a reason generated live from the new release's knowledge graph.
In the memory graph, that red cluster is the stale knowledge, isolated in its own dataset.
Stale memory doesn't get archived — it gets forgotten. One click, Cognee's surgical forget, that dataset only.
Same search, seconds later — the answer has flipped to the current fix. The durable incident history survived untouched.
I accept the fix, and improve reinforces it — the next recall ranks it even higher.
There's even a conversational layer — same memory, session-aware follow-ups.
And the operations feed shows everything you just watched, as lifecycle events:
remembered, recalled, drift caught, forgotten, reinforced. The memory is alive — you can see it think.
Remember, recall, improve, forget — every lifecycle verb load-bearing, self-hosted on the open-source stack:
Kuzu, LanceDB, SQLite. The whole loop runs in twenty seconds.
PatchPilot — every bug remembers its history.